American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IId. 1837-1844 APS.Archives.IId APS.Archives.IId
American Philosophical Society
American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IId
1837-1844
APS.Archives.IId
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the American Philosophical Society Archives. For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
American Philosophical Society.
- Papers
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for the Magellanic prize money, Jan.6, 1837; 4x8; Espy, James P. (James Pollard), 1785-1860
    Scope and Contents note
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 7, 1837; 10x8; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, L.S.: J. Prinsep. 1p. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 7, 1837; 8x5; Carey, Mathew, 1760-1839
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 9, 1837; 10x8; Royal Irish Academy
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jos.H.Singer. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 11, 1837; 10x8; Richards, Benjamin Wood, 1797-1851
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Forwards volume.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American Philosophical Society, Jan. 11, 1837; 10x8; Royal Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Chas. Konig. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Jan. 15, 1837; Roux de Rochelle, 1762-1849
  - Letter to J.K. Kane, January 19, 1837; 7 3/4" x 10 1/4"; Roux de Rochelle, 1762-1849
    secretary of the A.P.S. Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Acknowledges election to membership in the Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 28, 1837; 10x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, L.S. 1p. and add.,end. Forwards publication from the royal society.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American Philosophical Society, Feb. 3, 1837; 9-1/2x8; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    A.L.S.: Arthur Aikin. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 13, 1837; 10x7-1/2; United States. Dept. of State
    Dept. of State, L.S.: John Forsyth. 1p. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural history vol. 2, no. 85.) Acknowledges letters. Not found May, 2011.
  - List of documents deposited in the Bank of the United States on account of the American Philosophical Society, February 16, 1837; 7 7/8" x 12"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D. Deeds, loans, bonds, mortgages, insurance policies, receipts.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the paper entitled "Observations on bills of mortality... " [by James Mease, Philadelphia], February 17, 1837; 7 3/4" x 13"; American Philosophical Society
    6 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: G[eorge] Emerson, N[athaniel] Chapman, B[enjamin] R. Morgan. Publication not recommended. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 699.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 18, 1837; 10x8; McKenney, Thomas Loraine, 1785-1859
    Philadelphia, L.S.: Tho. L. McKenney and James Hale and Edwd C. Biddle. 1p. and end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American Philosophical Society, Feb. 25, 1837; 9-1/2x8; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    A.L.S.: Arthur Aikin. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - List of books needed to complete sets of journals, Feb., [1840]; 8-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society. Library
    or later. D. 1p. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 1, 1837; 10x8; Cadwalader, Thomas, 1779-1841
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards volumes from Granville Penn.
  - Resolution authorizing the historical and literary committee to publish DuPonceau's paper on Chinese languages, March 3, 1837; 8x5; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p.and end.
  - Resolutions concerning the committee on the observatory, March 3, 1837; 7 5/8" x 8 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.
  - Report... [Philadelphia], March 3, 1837; 4 7/8" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on finance
    2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Clement C. Biddle, George Ord. As to the investment of $1,300, $1,056.67 of which was realized on Joseph Priestley's bond.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, March 10, 1837; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
    London, L.S.: Wm. Yarrell. 1p. and add. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 14, 1837; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    L.S.: John Forsyth. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Report of committee on Judge Gibson's paper on U.S.geology, March 17, 1837; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Thos.Nuttall, Isaac Lea and Henry D. Rogers. 5p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.701.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 17, 1837; 10x8; Brigham, William, 1806-1869
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Friendly letter. Concerning donation.
  - Letter to Peter S. Duponceau, president of the A.P.S., March 17, 1837; 8" x 10"; McIlvaine, William, 1786-1854
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Resigns from Committee of finance.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 19, 1837; 10x7-1/2; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Glad the society likes his gift. Will sit for Sully whenever Sully comes to Washington. This item had been bound in Donation Book, Vol.I, date: Sept. 17, 1830.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 22, 1837; 8" x 10"; DeKay, J. E.
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. The Lyceum of Natural History inquires as to the cost of a complete set of the Transactions of the A.P.S.
  - Receipt to the American Philosophical Society for restoration of picture, March 22, 1837; 4-1/2x7-1/2; Scarlett, Samuel
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 27, 1837; 8" x 9 7/8"; Burrowes, Thomas H. (Thomas Henry), 1805-1871
    Secretary's Office, Harrisburg, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Will forward school reports to the A.P.S. "Nothing has yet been determined relative to the Historical Records ..."
  - Letter to Charles D. Meigs, March 30, 1837; 10x8; Macedo, Joaquim José da Costa de, 1777-1867
    Lisbon, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Acknowledges membership in the APS.
  - Letter to Charles D. Meigs, March 30, 1837; 10x8; Macedo, Joaquim José da Costa de, 1777-1867
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. In French. Acknowledges membership in APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 30, 1837; 10x8; Macedo, Joaquim José da Costa de, 1777-1867
    Lisbon, A.L.S. 3p.and end. In French. Thanks for membership to the APS. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 31, 1837; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Washington, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. "It cannot but be highly gratifying to me to find that the collection I was enabled to make and to present to our society is so highly appreciated."
  - List of books, March, 1837; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [together with number of volumes and prices thereof. Philadelphia, --, 2 pp. D.]
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, April 2, 1837; 8 1/4" x 10"; Almas, Paul Balogh de F.
    President of the A.P.S., Pest, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Returns thanks for "friendly attention" of A.P.S., especially for the interesting dissertations upon languages. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 3, 1837; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Warren, John Collins, 1778-1856
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. With regard to missing third volume of A.P.S. Transactions. Is going abroad in May, and would like letters of introduction to scientific men in France.
  - Letter to the President of the American Philosophical Society, April 8, 1837; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Copenhagen, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S.: thirteenth and fourteenth volumes of Hansen's work on public buildings in Denmark.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the Hungarian Academy of Sciences, April 10, 1837; 9-1/4x7-1/4; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Xerox of Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Franklin Bache. 1p.and end. (From original in Magyar Tudományos Akademia Konyvtara;1968.) Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 13, 1837; 10-1/2x8-1/2; New-York Historical Society
    New York, A.L.S. Frederick. 2p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication. Will forward their publications. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 14, 1837; 5" x 8"; Ingersoll, Charles Jared, 1782-1862
    Secretary of A.P.S., ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents old maps to the A.P.S.
  - Statement of accounts with the American Philosophical Society, April 14, 1837; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 18, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Parker, Daniel, 1782-1846
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Withdraws deposit of herbarium of the late Z[accheus] Collins from the A.P.S.
  - Letter to A. G. Jaudon, April 22, 1837; 10x8; Wilder, W. V. (?)
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.and enc.of bill of lading from Hottinguer & Co.and end. Forwards parcel to John Vaughan.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, April 24, 1837; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Josiah Quincy and Thaddeus William Harris. 1p. and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 26, 1837; 10x8; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    L.S.: J. Prinsep. 1p., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April, 1837; 5" x 7 3/4"; Parker, Daniel, 1782-1846
    [Philadelphia], --, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Order to deliver the herbarium of the late Z[accheus] Collins, deposited with A.P.S. in 1834, to C. S. Rafinesque.
  - Letter to the President of the American Philosophical Society of Philadelphia, May 1, 1837; 8 7/8" x 13 3/8"; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S.: Roux de Rochelle. (In French.) Forwards to the A.P.S.: Société de Géographie, Memoirs, V.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, May 2, 1837; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Tucker, George, 1775-1861
    Secretary of the A.P.S., University of Virginia, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to J[ohn] K. Kane, May 2, 1837; 8" x 9 5/8"; Winthrop, Thomas L. (Thomas Lindall), 1760-1841
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Boston, 1p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Report... [Philadelphia], May 5, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on the library
    1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: G[eorge] Ord, Isaac Hays, Charles Pickering. In re the books purchased by George Ord in Paris.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Charleston, May 8, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Bachman, John, 1790-1874
    1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends specimens of natural history, together with a communication, to A.P.S. See Minutes, May 19, 1837, in Pro. XXII, pt. 3, 704.
  - Letter to John Waughan [sic], Philadelphia, May 11, 1837; 10x-1/2x8-1/2; Morelli, Chevalier Domenico de
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Thanks for publications and will forward them to the king of Sicily.
  - Receipt to the American Philosophical Society for payment for books purchased by George Ord, May 11, 1837; 6x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D.S. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, May 16, 1837; 7 13/16" x 9 11/16"; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Cambridge, Mass., 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society. Printed: A.P.S. Proceedings, v.99, no.6,p.369.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 16, 1837; 10x8; Winthrop, Thomas L. (Thomas Lindall), 1760-1841
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Thanks for publications.
  - Receipt to the American Philosophical Society for casts of fossil bones, May 24, 1837; 3-1/2x8; Chitty, John
    D.S. 1p. In hand of J.Vaughan.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 28, 1837; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Short, Charles Wilkins, 1794-1863
    Librarian of A.P.S., Lexington, Ky., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Apologizes for bill of charges for the Transylvania Journal of Medicine. News of Dr. [L.] de Wette.
  - Letter to J. K. Kane, June 10, 1837; 8-1/2x8; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. Sends information concerning B.Franklin and the APS. On same sheet is account of the first project of the APS by B.Franklin; by [John Vaughan, June 10, 1837]. FILM54-64 FRAME129
  - Account of the first project of the American Philosophical Society by B.Franklin, June 10, 1837; 8-1/2x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 1p. On same sheet as letter from Jared Sparks to J.K.Kane; June 10, 1837. FILM54-64 FRAME130
  - Report of the committee upon John Bachman's paper, June 16, 1837; 5" x 8 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    "Observations on the changes of colour in birds and quadrupeds," [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: T[itian] R. Peale, G[eorge] Ord. Recommend publication in Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 16, 1837; 10x7-1/2; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. and add.,end. Forwards works on Franklin. FILM54-64 FRAME 99
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 18, 1837; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Warren, Jonathan Mason, 1811-1867
    Boston, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. With regard to missing third volume of A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, June 20, 1837; 8" x 9 13/16"; Forsyth, John, 1780-1841
    c/o John Vaughan, Department of State, [Washington, D.C.], Sends to the A.P.S.: documents of 24 Congress, 1 session.
  - Letter to the President of the APS, June 27, 1837; 11-1/2x8-1/2; Navarrete, Martín Fernández de, 1765-1844
    Madrid, L.S. 1p. In Spanish. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, July 6, 1837; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edward Charlesworth. 1p.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Papers pertaining to work done on Philosophical Hall, July 6, Nov. 15, 1837-1847; American Philosophical Society
    D. 181 items. Mostly paid by John Vaughan and George Ord. These items are in two folders. One contains dates of July 1837-Dec. 1841; the other Jan. 1842-Nov. 1847. They are filed together. Various sizes.
  - Letter to ----, July 14, 1837; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Prichard, James C. Cowles, 1786-1848
    Bristol, [England], 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 28, 1837; 9-1/2x8; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 58.) Audubon wishes to borrow certain Lewis and Clark journals. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 30, 1837; 9x7; Rönne, Friedrich Ludwig v., 1795-1865
    Newport, R.I., A.L.S. 2p.and add. Will forward APS publications to Germany.
  - Remarks..., August 1, 1837; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Abert, John James, 1788-1863
    upon the mocking bird. ----, 4 pp. and endorsement. Com. Read, August 18, 1837. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 705.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Aug. 6, 1837; 13-1/4x9; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Roux de Rochelle. 1p.and end. by J.Vaughan. Thanks for Transactions received through Warden. Needs additional volume to complete series.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American Philosophical Society, Aug. 7, 1837; 10-1/2x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Arago. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 8, 1837; 9x7; Royal Dublin Society
    A.L.S.: Isaac Weld. 2p.and add. Thanks for publications.
  - Concerning Phosphorescent lights, Aug. 9, 1837; 10x7-1/2; Conyngham, Redmond, 1781-1846
    Oak Hill, A.D.S. 1p.and add.: "John Vaughan.", end. (see Ms.comm. to the APS. Natural Philosophy, Vol. 2, no. 89.) Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American Philosophical Society, Aug. 10, 1837; 10x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Boeckh. 1p.,end. In German. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Aug. 10, 1837; 10-1/2x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Boeckh. 1p.,end. In German. Thanks for publications.
  - Book containing the laws and regulations and a list of members of the Society submitted for inspection by the secretaries, August 18, 1837; 8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. D.S.: Franklin Bache, J[ohn] K. Kane.
  - Letter to J[ohn] K. Kane, August 18, 1837; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Leslie, Charles Robert, 1794-1859
    Secretary to the A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Aug. 19, 1837; 8x5; Société des antiquaires de France
    Paris, L.S.: G. Mortomer. 1p.,end. In French. Has received publication.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical society, Aug. 19, 1837; 8-1/4x5; Société asiatique (Paris, France)
    Paris, L.S.: Hangoumar. 1p. In French. Thanks for Transactions.which were forwarded by Warden.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 21, 1837; 10x7; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Ms.Comm. to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 59.) Concerning the Lewis and Clark manuscripts in the APS. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to Baron Roenne, Aug. 21, 1837; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Letterpress copy. Concerning APS publications to be forwarded abroad.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 23, Sept. 4, 1837; 10x8; Imperatorskai︠a︡ akademīi︠a︡ nauk i khudozhestv (Russia)
    St. Petersbourg, Printed D. filled in in ms.S.: Fuss. 1p. and end. In French. Thanks for publications. Not found May, 2011.
  - Receipt to J[oh]n Vaughan for gold images from Bogatá, Aug. 24, 1837; 4X8; Gibbon, J. H.
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p.and end. See also letter from Gibbon to John Vaughan; Aug. 25, 1837.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 24, 1837; 10x8; Rebello, José Silvestre, d. 1844
    Rio, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, ----, August 25, 1837; 7 3/4" x 12 3/8"; Gibbon, J. H.
    1 p. A.L.S. Concerning five gold figures, found on the site of an Indian village near Bogota, and now offered to the A.P.S. (See Minutes, August 18, 1837.)
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, August 28, 1837; 7 5/8" x 9 1/2"; Coates, Raynell, 1802-1886
    President of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Transmits the thanks of the scientific corps of the U.S. Exploring Expedition for "the completion of the collection of Books required for the... Expedition."
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 4, 1837; 7 15/16" x 9 13/16"; Hopkinson, Francis, 1781-1870
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Presents one of the "Old Congress Chairs" to the A.P.S. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau and others, September 11, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Dickerson, Mahlon, 1770-1853
    Navy Department, [Washington, D.C.], 1 p. A.L.S. Returns thanks for report of the 2d., in re the South Sea Exploring Expedition.
  - Letter to the President and members of the American Philosophical Society, September 12, 1837; 7 13/16" x 9 15/16"; Pickering, Charles, 1805-1878
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Tenders his resignation from membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 28, 1837; 10x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, L.S.: Werthe. 1p. In French. Thanks for publications.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper by George W. Miller entitled, October 6, 1837; 8" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    "A concise method of extracting the cube root," [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] M. Patterson, Henry Vethake, Hartman Bache. Publication not recommended.
  - Letter to the President of the Philosophical Society of Philadelphia (sic), October 17, 1837; 8 1/4" x 11"; Société royale des antiquaires de France
    Paris, 1 p. L.S. (In French.) Forwards to the A.P.S.: Memoirs, XIII.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American Philosophical Society, Oct. 18, 1837; 9x7-1/2; Zoological Society of London
    L.S.: Edward Charlesworth. 1p., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 21, 1837; 10x8; Hornbeck, H. B.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to ----, Oct. 23, 1837; 12x8; Real Academia de la Historia
    Madrid, L.S.: Gabriel Jose Garcia. 1p. In Spanish. Thanks for APS publications.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, October 23, 1837; 7 5/8" x 9 5/8"; Walker, Sears Cook, 1805-1853
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. A.N.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, Oct. 31, 1837; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: John Forsyth. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, November 1, 1837; 7 3/4" x 10"; Dunlap, Thomas, ca. 1792-1864
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, Nov. 2, 1837; 13-1/2x8-3/4; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: R.Hutton. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to J[ohn] K. Kane, November 2, 1837; 8" x 9 7/8"; Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852
    Boston, 1 p. L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to P[eter] S. DuPonceau, November 3, 1837; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Jenks, William, 1778-1866
    President of the A.P.S., Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 9, 1837; 9x7; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: F.Boott. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 10, 1837; 10x8; Bartlett, John Russell, 1805-1886
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards publications.from the Royal society of northern antiquities.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 10, 1837; 8" x 9 7/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Amsterdam, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Relative to affairs of A.P.S.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Vaughan, London, Nov.13, 1837; 9x7-1/2; Cambridge Philosophical Society
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.S. Newlow. 1p. and add. Thanks for APS publication.
  - List of manuscripts presented to the American Philosophical Society, November 17, 1837; 8" x 12"; American Philosophical Society
    by Lieut. [Sylvanus] Godon, U. S. Navy. [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D. Also includes list of printed works presented by Lieut. Godon.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 17, 1837; 9-3/4x8-1/4; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Nicholas Carlisle. 1p.and add.,end. "by favour of Wm.Vaughan, Esqr" Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 20, 1837; 10x8; Thurston, James, 1806-1872
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p., add. Friendly letter. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, November 26, 1837; 10x8; Royal Society of London